# KARTHIKEYAN NS

## Senior Software Engineer .NET

9551415713 @ learnerkarthik@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nskofficia/

#### **SUMMARY**

Experienced Software Engineer with a passion for developing scalable systems that are relatable and user-friendly which expedite the efficiency and effectiveness of the organization. Over 3+ years of experience in .NET Core Web Applications, Web API & SQL Server. Having a clear understanding of front-end technologies such as REACT.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Senior Software Engineer

07/2021 - Ongoing

Calcium

Coimbatore, India

- Worked with members of the software development and testing team to develop and implement robust solutions that meet product requirements for functionality, scalability and performance.
- Involved in three phases of SDLC Requirement Analysis, Implementation and Testing.
- Worked with Technologies like C#, .NET Core Web API, Entity Framework Core, React, Redux, Javascript, SQL Server, Azure functions and written test functions using AutoMock.
- Having good debugging skills to figure out the root cause of the problem.
- Worked with different 3rd party health APIs such as Health Gorilla, Health IT and Azure FHIR Service.
- Single-handedly implemented .NET Machine learning framework that is used to predict the health score based on various inputs from the user.
- Took part in the development of the Microservice project, which is used to implement AB Testing management functionality in the product.
- Beginner level knowledge of Azure Services.

#### Software Engineer

11/2018 - 06/2021

#### **SPAN Technology Services**

Chennai, India

- Worked in an Agile team of .NET developers for a fast-paced software development company.
- Worked with U.S based web applications for the Trucking business and Tax filings.
- Used .NET Core MVC pattern, Entity framework, C#, HTML, CSS, Jquery, and SQL Server to design and develop web-based solutions, both front end and back end
- Analyzed and implemented Google OAuth sign-up functionality.

#### Java Intern

06/2018 - 07/2018

#### **FULL Creative**

Chennai, India

Learnt Core Java for a month that included daily Q&A sessions with the mentor.



## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science

Rajalakshmi Engineering College

Chennai, India

## **SKILLS**

C# · .NET Core Web API ·

EF Core · React · Redux ·

Javascript · SQL Server ·

Azure Functions · MVC

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Core JAVA from NIIT

Ceritfied System Architect from PEGA Systems

#### **LANGUAGES**

**English** 

Telugu

Tamil